Guide to the Oliver and Ellen Ricketts Papers 1923-1973
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Oliver and Ellen Ricketts Papers
1923-1973
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 354
Ricketts Family
2 containers. 1 linear feet of shelf space. 350 items.
Correspondence, financial and other papers concerning real estate, education, finances and the settlement of estates of the Ricketts family of Pullman and Seattle.
Oliver Preston Ricketts, born October 27, 1879, and his wife Ellen (Clark) Ricketts, born August 3, 1883, were long time residents of Pullman. The couple had four children: Mrs. Auril Brown, Bernard, Evelyn (d.1925), and Vernon. Mrs. Ricketts graduated from Washington State University in 1933, and was subsequently engaged in social work with the King County Welfare Department. Mr. Ricketts was a Post Office mail carrier for twenty-seven years.
After retirement, the Ricketts managed their Pullman apartment building and Mrs. Ricketts pursued her interest in family and pioneer history. Mrs. Ricketts passed away in her eighty-fifth year on September 23, 1968 and Mr. Ricketts followed on October 5, 1971 at the age of ninety-one years.
The Oliver and Ellen Ricketts collection, dated 1923 through 1973, comprises seven series. Series one is the estate papers of Mr. and Mrs. Ricketts. Washington State University honorary society certificates and academic transcripts for Mrs. Ricketts and her daughter, Auril Ricketts, in addition to Mrs. Ricketts' social work professional papers, complete series two. The third series includes correspondence generated by family members and friends.
The Ricketts' personal financial records comprise series four while income tax data and Whitman County tax statements make up series five. Series six consists of maps, real estate agreements, assessment notices, and correspondence related to a lot in Juanita Crest division in Seattle owned by the Ricketts. The final series contains miscellaneous papers and a commonplace book.
Papers are ordered chronologically within each series.
This collection is open for research use.
The Oliver and Ellen Ricketts papers were donated to the Washington State University Libraries by Mrs. Bernard Ricketts in October 1977.
Related materials will be found in the papers of the Clark Family ( Cage 77) and Bernard Ricketts ( Cage 355).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Ricketts, Oliver Preston, 1875-1971--Archives; Ricketts, Ellen Adeline Clark, 1883-1968; Ricketts, Bernard, Mrs., donor. WaPS
Ricketts family
Home and Family; City Planning; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: Estates
  - Ellen (Clark) Ricketts Estate, 1963-1971; 75 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Oliver P. Ricketts Estate, 1968-1973; 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Educational and Professional
  - King County Welfare Department, 1941-1952; 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Washington State University, 1932-1952; 10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Correspondence
  - Personal Correspondence, 1923-1968; 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Myrtle (Ricketts) Johnson, 1968-1969; 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series 4: Finances
  - Banking, 1942-1968; 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Retirement and Social Security, 1961-1971; 15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Financial Records, 1969-1972; 60 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series 5: Taxes
  - Income Taxes, 1955-1972; 35 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Whitman County Taxes, 1933-1936; 7 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series 6: Juanita Crest Lot
  - Juanita Crest Lot, 1947-1968; 75 (Box 2, Folder 14-19)
- Series 7: Other Papers
  - Commonplace Book, undated; 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1941-1966; 28 (Box 2, Folder 21)